Skills

Azure Cloud Technologies,

Azure DevOps

C# | Asp.Net Core

Angular | TypeScript

NodeJs | JavaScript

Sql Server | MongoDb

Git | GitHub

Xamarin / Ionic for mobile

Qualifications

BCom (Informatics) 2004 University of South Africa

Over 20 years of industry experience developing software solutions.

Info / Contact

+27 (0)60 840 7793

allen@codestream.co.za

Please see my personal and company websites for more details on my skills and experience.

www.codestream.co.za

www.allenfirth.info

Online Profiles

LinkedIn

GitHub

Allen Firth

Architect / Developer

Profile

I have over <u>20 years of industry experience</u> developing software solutions and leading development teams for large corporates and small start-ups.

I am a <u>full stack developer</u> highly skilled in Microsoft technologies and the Azure cloud platform. I have extensive experience in object orientated architecture, systems design and development as well as coding practices, specifically test-driven development, agile and XP approaches.

I have been exposed to various industries and sectors as well as to all aspects of the software development lifecycle from project conception through analysis, design and implementation and finally, to deployment, maintenance and support of the final product.

Experience

2017 - Current, CodeStream

I am involved in various internal projects at **The SPAR Group**. I built the Vendor master data management user interface using **Angular** and **C# Apis**.

I was instrumental in development of SPAR's central DataLake reporting database (SQL Server) which I later migrated to the Azure Cloud using Azure Data Factory and Azure Synapse.

I provide ongoing support for the above systems. Please see <u>allenfirth.info</u> for more detail on projects I've worked on through my company CodeStream.

2014 - 2017, SMEasy (CTO, Architect and Developer)

I was CTO for a small FinTech start-up operating out of <u>Durban, South Africa</u>. SMEasy provided an easy-to-use online accounting package for small to medium enterprises.

I was instrumental in redirecting the architecture and technology choices of the product as well as leading and directing a near re-write of the system using modern frameworks and introducing cutting edge development practises to the development team. SMEasy was developed using **Angular**, **C#**, **Asp.Net** and **Azure SQL Server** and Azure DevOps.

2008 – 2014, London United Kingdom, Various contracts

I spent six and a half years plying my trade as a sought-after software developer in **London**. I gained experience working with top talent in large corporate environments such as <u>Man Investments</u>, <u>BritInsurance</u> and <u>Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer</u>. I spent the last three years in London working for a Software development consultancy called <u>Digiterre</u> and working on various projects for the likes of <u>EDF</u> and <u>M&G Asset Management</u>.